<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Machine Learning on Youniverse</title><link>https://youniverse.site/tags/machine-learning/</link><description>Recent content in Machine Learning on Youniverse</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 15:23:23 +1100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://youniverse.site/tags/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Coursera | Machine Learning Specialisation (0/n)</title><link>https://youniverse.site/posts/2023/01/coursera-machine-learning-specialisation-0/n/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 15:23:23 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://youniverse.site/posts/2023/01/coursera-machine-learning-specialisation-0/n/</guid><description>Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking of picking up machine learning as it may be interesting to work on some toy projects. I started working on the Machine Learning Specialisation on Coursera. To me, Prof. Andrew Ng&amp;rsquo;s Machine Learning course on Coursera is one of the go-to material to get started with Machine Learning. This is my second time learning this course on Coursera, and the first time I did it, it was not yet a specialisation.</description></item><item><title>Coursera | Machine Learning Specialisation (2/n) - Supervised Learning</title><link>https://youniverse.site/posts/2023/01/coursera-machine-learning-specialisation-2/n-supervised-learning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 15:11:00 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://youniverse.site/posts/2023/01/coursera-machine-learning-specialisation-2/n-supervised-learning/</guid><description>Supervised Learning ℹ️ *Supervised machine learning*, or *supervised learning*, refers to algorithms that learn the input to output, or $x$ to $y$, mapping.
The key characteristic of supervised learning is that you give your learning algorithm examples to learn from, i.e., the training set, which include the right answers, i.e., the correct label $y$ for a given input $x$. With the correct pairs of input $x$ and desired output label $y$, the learning algorithm learns to take just the input alone without the output label and gives a reasonably accurate prediction of the output.</description></item><item><title>Coursera | Machine Learning Specialisation (1/n) - Overview</title><link>https://youniverse.site/posts/2022/12/coursera-machine-learning-specialisation-1/n-overview/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 14:10:34 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://youniverse.site/posts/2022/12/coursera-machine-learning-specialisation-1/n-overview/</guid><description>The current version is a specialisation consisting three courses:
Supervised Machine Learning: Regression and Classification; Advanced Learning Algorithms; Unsupervised Learning, Recommenders, Reinforcement Learning. This article is a brief summary of Machine Learning taken from the specialisation.
The first course in the specialisation, &amp;ldquo;Supervised Machine Learning: Regression and Classification&amp;rdquo;, provides a brief summary of the machine learning domain and goes introduces the details of supervised machine learning.
Machine Learning ℹ️ Machine learning (ML) is the science of getting computers to learn without being explicitly programmed.</description></item></channel></rss>